

# KYRAN STAGG

Software Engineer

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a well-organized, creative, and team-oriented software engineering professional. I enjoy hockey, running, table-top games and above all, people!
I have experience working in full stack development and in agile teams. I have proven experience in building web applications with frontend JavaScript frameworks, while also building RESTful API micro-service backends with PostgreSQL

#### CONTACT

+44 793 207 4142

<u>krs19@live.com</u>

linkedin.com/in/kyran-stagg

github.com/GEOFAIRY

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Software Engineer Admiral Insurance

Cardiff, Wales

March 2023 - Present

- Senior Front-end engineer building the quoting site for the largest insurance provider in Wales.
- Responsible for multiple major framework upgrades to the entry point website
- Mentored a team of developers and testers.
- Worked closely with product team to produce new features and guide them to deliver excellent solutions.
- Worked to improve code committing and documentation standards.
- Supported systems build with Angular, Node, Azure, and Java

#### **DEVELOPER**

## Education Payroll Limited Wellington, New Zealand

November 2022 – January 2023

- Intermediate Full stack developer working on the largest payroll system in New Zealand
- Delivered strike and employment agreement change features build in a short timeframe of one month.
- Utilized skills to redefine the Angular front end and enhance Dotnet backend.
- Worked closely with junior developers to enable them to build long lasting, clean front-end code.
- Worked on UI enhancement proposals in Figma.

#### **DEVELOPER**

**Lovalty NZ** 

Wellington, New Zealand

January 2022 - November 2022

- Intermediate Full stack developer working on the Flybuys rewards website and cloud applications.
- Accountable for maintaining New Zealand's largest marketing data set with over 3 million users.
- Maintained existing Ruby on Rails site and Ruby microservices in AWS.
- Responsible for migrating legacy Rails site to Typescript-Next.js (React)
- Handled support requests in a rotated roster.
- Moved development environments from local manual setups to Docker containers.
- Integrated code style and linting for company projects with an included write up of explanations

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

University of Canterbury, Christchurch, New Zealand

### **EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

Field Hockey Player

2004 - 2015

Field Hockey Coach

2011-2014

BYOD I.T. Support

2015

Youth Group Leader

2018

Rock Climber & Boulderer

2020 - Present

#### **QUALIFICATIONS**

#### 2016-2019

Graduated in April 2020

### CONTACT

+44 793 207 4142

linkedin.com/in/kyran-stagg

github.com/GEOFAIRY

#### DEVELOPER

#### Arlo Training management software Lower Hutt, New Zealand

April 2021 – December 2021

- Lead Developer in the Website Integration Team
- Created full integrations on client websites to promote and sell their training courses.
- Responsible for the maintenance of the Arlo web controls library and WordPress plugin.
- Upgraded Arlo widgets to use SCSS and ES6
- Implemented azure pipelines to test, format & lint code submitted by any web dev.
- Worked in an agile format running standups and using scrum boards.
- Worked with clients to create heavily customized integrations instead of usual integrations.
- Redefined web team integration creation processes
- Trained new developer and helped with training new designer.

#### WEB SUPPORT SPECIALIST

#### Arlo Training management software Lower Hutt, New Zealand

October 2020 – April 2021

- Key Role in the Arlo 'Web Team' handling ad hoc coding/integration tasks; small integrations, sales, support, and administration.
- Worked on production sites to ensure delivery of training events for many clients.
- Used JavaScript, HTML, CSS and jQuery to meet client requirements.
- Handled all web related support queries.
- Managed the 'Integration Developer's' tasks with Dynamics, Azure boards and Git to ensure delivery of client integration on time.

### **SKILLS**

	<b>Technical Skills</b>	
JavaScript	NodeJs	VueJs
ReactJs	Angular	HTML5
SCSS	AWS	Azure
Java	Spark	JavaFx
Xamarin	Kotlin	Knockout.js
C#	SQL	Python
Django	RESTful API's	Docker
Maven	C++	OAuth
Google Maps	GDPR	SQLite
Ruby	Rails	Angular